You're a parasite.
あなたは寄生虫　楽な生き方よね
What an easy way to live.
I want to become stronger.
オレはもっと強くなりてぇ 自分の怒りを抑えられるほど
...Strong enough to keep my own anger in check.
Takashi! Takashi! Takashi!
隆志…
Saika's purpose is to love people.
罪歌の目的はね 人間を愛することさ
Let's all love each other!
みんなで愛し合いましょう
I guess it's okay to use all of it now.
全力出していいんだよな？
I live by feeding off Saika, who loves people for me.
私の代わりに人を愛する罪歌に依存して
寄生して 生きてるんです
Oh, Anri.
ほら　杏里　高い高～い
You're up so high!
That's a lie...
それは　偽り…
よかったわね　杏里
And that's the truth...
それは　真実…
Heiwajima Shizuo...
平和島… 平和島静雄
I love you...
He's so strong...
強い…
No...
いや…　怖い
He's scary...
No...
いや…　かっこいい！
He's so cool!
I...
こいつ 強い強いと思ってはいたけど
...knew he was incredibly strong, but...
I didn't know he was THIS strong...
ここまでとは…
Something happened, didn't it?
なんかあったんじゃねぇか？
How about you go see what it is?
ちょっと見てきたらどうだ？
You're not doing anything anyway, right?
どっちにしろ お前　今　なんもしてねぇだろ？
Those are made of the same stuff as my scythe.
鎌と同じ特別製だ
They'll stop something as weak as a blade.
刃物ぐらいなら　受け止められる
Thanks.
ありがとよ
Well then...
さてと…
That katana...is Saika?!
その刀… まさか 罪歌
Then, before...the one who attacked me was...?
じゃあ あのとき私を襲ったのは…
You even did that to your own parents?!
あなた…自分の両親も？
It looks like you didn't teach the children
spawned from your Saika how to fight.
そっちの罪歌の子供は戦い方までは教えてくれなかったんですね
I have a favor to ask.
お願いです ほかの罪歌にやめるように言ってください
Please tell the other Saikas to stop.
They should stop if you, the parent, tell them to.
親であるあなたが命令すれば
子供たちは止まるはずです
I could also order them to stop by possessing you with my parent Saika...
あなたが罪歌に乗っ取られていれば
その更に親である私の罪歌から命令することもできるんですけど…
That's impossible!
そんなはずない！
I've suppressed Saika!
私は罪歌を抑えつけた愛の力で！
With the power of love!
To have someone like you who doesn't even know how to love...!
愛を知らないあなたなんかに！
I'll let you listen to something for a bit.
少しだけ聞かせてあげます
It's what's perpetually echoing inside of me:
私の中にいつもいつも響いている
Saika's...
罪歌の愛の言葉を…
Words of love...
I love you.
愛してる…
I love people very much.
好き…
I love you.
とても人が好きよ どうしたら…
No!
違うわ！
人間がみんなみんな好きなの
That was a lie...
それは 偽りだった
Stop it!
やめて！
And that was the truth...
それが 現実だった
Her dad, who ran an antique shop...
やめて！
古物商だった彼女の父は
...would blow off steam by...
うまくいかない商売のうっぷんを家族への暴力で晴らした
...beating his family.
And, little by little, she closed herself off.
次第に彼女は 心を閉ざすようになった
That was when...
そのころだった斬り裂き魔が現れたのは
the Slasher appeared.
I love you.
I love...you.
愛しているわ あなた
Her mother was the Slasher.
斬り裂き魔の正体は母だった
I like you.
愛してる  愛してる 好きよ
I love you.
私を愛して…
ただ一つ 言葉があればいいの
愛してるよ 愛してる…
Our love should have cut into him.
確かに 私たちの愛は刻まれたはずなのに…
Once we injure someone, our thoughts
should flow into his body via fear and pain...
一度 傷を付ければ恐怖と痛みを媒介して
思念が 流れ込むはずなのに
恐怖を感じていない？ 平和島静雄は
...but he doesn't feel fear...
Heiwajima Shizuo doesn't...
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
Don't misunderstand;
勘違いしてるんじゃねぇぞてめぇら
No one loves me because they're afraid of me...
みんなが怖がるからオレは誰にも愛されない？
Don't make me laugh.
笑わせんな 怖いのはオレの方なんだ
I'm the one who's scared!
I can't control this power...
てめぇの力を抑えきれなくて
...and I'm constantly afraid of failing.
いつも何かしくじっちまうんじゃないかって
That's right, I'm the biggest coward in the world.
そう、オレは世界一の臆病者だ
But so what if I am?
だが それがどうした
The fact that I'm a coward has nothing
to do with beating the crap out of you.
オレが臆病なこととてめぇらをぶちのめすことに なんの関係もありゃしねぇ
Besides, I can't go down...
それによ
オレのことを愛してくれるヤツの前で倒れるわけにはいかないだろ？
...in front of the people who love me.
How...
なんで そんな声に耐えられるの？
...can you stand that voice?
I have many deficiencies.
私は いろいろと足りない人間なんです
That's why I leech off things—to make up for what I lack.
だから足りない何かを補うために
いろいろな何かに寄生して生きている
I don't have the heart to love people, so I can bear this voice forever.
私には人を愛する心が足りないから
ずっとこの声を聞き続けられるんです
Forever and ever, objectively—
ずっとずっと客観的に
I did it!
やったわ！
That's right, I'd never lose to you...
そうよ 私があんたなんかに！
Why are you afraid?
なぜ 怖がるんですか？
Being slashed is an outcome of love, isn't it?
斬るのは 愛の結果なんでしょう？
You let me slash you?!
わざと斬られたの？ どうして？
Why?!
I'm going to do something terrible to you.
これから あなたに少しひどいことをします
So now I won't owe you anything.
だからこれで 貸し借りなしです
I'm going to have my Saika possess you.
あなたの心を私の罪歌に乗っ取らせてもらいます
I won't apologize.
謝りませんよ
If I do, that would mean I'd have to contradict my way of life.
ここでまた謝ったら 私の生き方を否定することになりますから
I don't think I'm being fair...
私はずるいんだと思います
Since I'm trying to protect my peaceful
life by doing something terrible to you.
あなたにひどいことをして自分の平穏を守ろうとしているんですから
But, I can't help it...
でもしかたがないんですよ
...because I'm a parasite.
寄生虫ですから…
I love you.
Saika gets lonely easily.
罪歌は さみしがり屋なんです
From our point of view, it may seem wrong...
私たちから見たら間違っているかもしれないけど
But it truly does love people.
人間が本当に好きなんです
So, please love Saika, Niekawa.
だから 愛してあげてください
贄川先輩も罪歌のことを
Because—unlike me—you have the ability to love people.
先輩は 私と違って人を愛することができるんですから
Stop!
止まれ！止まりやがれ～！
Just frigging stop!
Huh?
How'd we get like this?!
なんで こんなとこに…
何？何？
So, no one died, huh?
くたばったヤツは一人もいねぇか
Where am I?
Finally...
やっと… やっとオレの言うこと聞いてくれたな
It finally listened to me.
Anri! Is that you, Anri?!
杏里！杏里なのか？
She came after me and tried to slash me before.
そいつは 前にオレに斬りつけてきてな
I had her transferred so she wouldn't become a problem.
問題にならないよう転校させてたんだ
I guess she hasn't given—
まだあきらめてなかった…
Anri, let's get out of here!
杏里 一緒に逃げよう！
Sonohara, I helped you out, didn't I?
園原 お前には目を掛けてやっただろう？
Yeah, with the Harima thing!
そうだ 張間だ！
Who do you think put you and Harima in the same class?
張間と同じクラスになれたのは誰のお陰だと…
I've already paid you back for that.
その借りは もう返しました
P-Paid me back...?
か… 返したって 今のでか？
You mean with what you just did?
I thought that the black biker was the Slasher.
私は 黒バイクさんが斬り裂き魔だと思ってました
So I figured he'd attack you...
だから先生が襲われるんだと思って
I got lost in that thought...I wanted to help you...
無我夢中で先生を助けたくって…
Eh?
It's not because I like you.
先生が好きだったからじゃありません
I just wanted to pay off my debt to you at all costs.
先生への借りは絶対に返しておきたかったから
What're you talking about?
なんの話だ？
Why was the black biker chasing you?
先生は どうして黒バイクさんに追われていたんですか？
What in the world did you do?
一体何をやったんですか？
Oh...
He's...from back then...
こいつ あのときの…
What are you...
何って…
Anri!
杏里…なんだ？そんなもの持って…
What are you doing with that?
Y-You too? Are you like that, too?!
お…お前もか？
Will you also...
お前もなのか？お前もオレを…
No, I'm different from Niekawa...
いいえ 私は 贄川先輩とは違います
Because...I loathe you.
私は 先生のこと大嫌いですから
We've got a prepubescent, flat-chested girl now!
ツルペタ きた
Come to think of it, what new pocket
editions did Dengeki release this month?
これ～ ふふっ そういえば今月の電撃文庫の新刊って
You can't use this car for evil, huh?
この車 使って悪いことはできねぇな
Yeah, that's it.
Oh, that's right.
そうだ 「キノの旅」って新章に突入したりしないんっすか？
Have they started making new chapters of "Kino's Journey?"
Maybe they'll release a "Shizu's Journey!"
ははっ「シズの旅」とか 出ないかな？
That Samoyed Mask would...
サモエド仮面が こんなに…
Even though you knew how it'd turn out if
you asked Yumasaki to take care of it...psh.
遊馬崎に頼んだらこうなるのが分かってたのによ くそっ！
Oh, Togusa, your face is red.
あれ？渡草さん 顔 赤い
Maybe you have a fever?
熱でもあるんじゃないっすか？
I'll never forgive you!
うるせぇ～～!!
Are you sure you're okay, Sonohara?
本当に大丈夫？ 園原さん
Yeah.
うん 大したことないから
It's nothing serious.
I was surprised when I heard the news from Masaomi.
正臣に聞いて びっくりしたよ
Are you really okay?
本当に大丈夫なの？
And, where exactly is Masaomi...?
で その正臣はどこに…
He went home earlier.
さっき 帰りました何か 用があるって
He said he had something to take care of.
Honestly, what could he have to do at a time like this?
ったくこんなときに なんの用だよ…
There's really nothing wrong with me.
本当に何もないから
Have you talked with the police yet?
警察には話したの？
I heard a lot of other people besides you got hurt—
園原さんのほかにさ 大勢被害に遭ったって
It's fine.
もう いいんです
No, it's not!
よくないよ！
I have a feeling...that nothing else will happen.
たぶんもう何も起こらないようなそんな気がするんです
Why?
どうして？
Oh, sorry.
ごめんなさい 実はケガをする何時間か前にも一回斬り裂き魔に襲われてたんです
Actually, I was attacked by the Slasher a few hours before I got hurt.
At the time, a lot of people helped me out...
そのときいろんな人が助けてくれて
And one of them was really cool...
その中にかっこいい人がいて…
One of them was cool?
かっ… かっこいい人？
What the hell is this development?
何？この展開
Yes, a sunglasses-wearing bartender and...
ええ サングラスを掛けたバーテンさんと…
Eh, that couldn't be Shizuo, could it?!
そ… それってまさか静雄さん!?
And there was another extremely cool person...
もう一人の人がすごくかっこよくて
Please don't be surprised when I tell you.
驚かないでくださいね
Umm...
あの首なしライダーさんなんです
It was the headless rider!
Err, uh, umm...
Wait a second!
ちょっと待って！
We talked a little bit, but he was very proactive, and I could tell he has a love of others...
少しお話ししたんですけど
すごい行動的で人を愛することができて…
You don't believe me, do you?
こんなこと信じてもらえませんよね？
I wouldn't say "don't believe..."
信じるというか…
"He" is a girl!
あの人 女だよ!?
And when I was attacked again, it
was the headless rider who saved me!
その後 襲われたときも また首なしライダーさんが助けてくれたんです
So, I think I'll be okay now.
だからもう大丈夫だと思うんです
But, he's...
いや だから あの人は…
I can't say it.
言えない
I mean, if I do...
だって それを言ったら…
Well, but, they're in a completely
different world from us normal people...
いや… でも ああいう人たちは僕たちの日常とはずっと遠くにいる人たち
So you probably shouldn't get too involved...
だからあんまり かかわらない方が…
Ryugamine, what do you think real
abnormality is in this world of ours?
竜ヶ峰君この世で本当の非日常ってなんだと思いますか？
Huh?
It's having nothing happen. It's when nothing happens over and over, day in and day out.
何も起こらないこと
毎日毎日同じことの繰り返しで何も起きない
It's having nothing change.
何も変わらない それが本当の…
That's the real...
I'll have a doctor I know take a look at her.
この子は知り合いの医者に診せる 安心してくれ
Don't worry.
Celty, umm...I...
セルティさん あの… 私…
Don't apologize!
謝るな 自分が正しいと思うことをやったんだろ？
You only did what you thought was right, didn't you?
Actually, I think you did the right thing, too.
実際あの場じゃ あれが正しいと思う
Well, I do think that knocking my head off was going
a bit too far, but I'll have to take that up with Saika.
まあ 首を飛ばすのはやりすぎだとは思うが
それは罪歌に文句を言うとしよう
This doesn't mean I sympathize with you, though.
同情しているわけじゃないぞ
I just don't think I could beat you if we fought.
戦っても 勝てる気がしないだけだ
If you're still not satisfied, use that power you obtained to help others.
もし 納得できないというなら
君が手に入れた力を
この街のためのボランティア活動に使ってくれ
She had obtained a power;
彼女は 力を手に入れた
a power that enabled her to manipulate over 100 Saikas at will.
１００人を超える罪歌の集団を意のままに操れる力
That power weighed heavily on her.
その力を彼女は重荷に感じた
However, that's partly what she wished for.
だが それは彼女が望んでいたことでもあった
For someone like her who was always floating on the breeze,
宙をふらふらと浮いていた自分が
人の運命を握るという重圧によって
the pressure of holding people's fate in her hands finally made her feel firmly grounded in reality.
地面にしっかりと足を着けたような気がした
I may not be...
Then, she heard a voice.
そのとき 声が聞こえた
It said, "I may not be able to love you, but I don't hate you."
「あなたのことは愛せないけど 嫌いじゃない」
Or she may have just felt that she heard it.
聞こえたような気がしただけかもしれない
Even when she called out to it, it didn't respond.
問い返しても 返事はなかった
However, that was fine with her.
だが それでよかった
She became just a little bit happier.
ほんの少しだけうれしくなった
She had finally returned to a normal life.
彼女は今 やっと日常に戻ってきた
Yet, she couldn't tell them the truth;
だが本当のことを 彼らには言えない
the truth about Saika, or about who pulls the strings.
罪歌のこともこの事件の黒幕のことも
Now that she'd come to control every Saika, she was able to search through Niekawa Haruna's memory, and thus found out about him.
すべての罪歌を統べる存在になった彼女は
彼らから贄川春奈の記憶をたどり
その存在を知った
She didn't know his target...
目的は分からない
...but, if it happened to be either Mikado or Masaomi...
if he was trying to destroy their peaceful lives...
だが もしその人物が帝人や正臣
自分たちの平穏を壊そうというのなら…
Bathed in anxiety and resolve, she remembered his name.
不安と決意にまみれながら彼女は
黒幕の名前を思い出した
And that name is...
その名は…
Orihara Izaya certainly is an odd name.
折原臨也ってやっぱりおかしな名前よね
It may be a coincidence that I was raised this way, but I think it suits me perfectly.
こんなふうに育ったのは偶然かもしれないけど
自分じゃぴったりだと思ってるよ
How much do you believe in coincidence, Namie?
波江さんは偶然ってどこまで信じる？
What are you talking about?
なんの話？
They probably think all these happenings are mere coincidences...
彼らは今回のいろいろなことが偶然だと思っているんだろうなぁ
...even though I'm the one who lead Nasujima there during that timespan.
あの時間帯に那須島を行くようにしむけたのはオレなのにさ
Except, he was a complete idiot.
しかしあいつ本当にバカだったな
He could've found out Sonohara Anri's
address by just taking a look at the class list.
園原杏里の住所なんてクラス名簿を盗み見りゃ一発だろうに
Well, there are lots of things that exist if you
look for them with the idea that you'll find them.
いや それにしても「ある」っていう前提で調べると結構あるもんだね
Like ethereal swords or faeries...
妖刀とか 妖精というもんはさ
Yeah, what actually was an accident was when he took my money and ran.
そう 本当に偶然だったのは那須島がオレの金をとって逃げたとき
You idiot!
Once he'd fallen into debt, Nasujima blackmailed the parents...
借金に追われていた
How much do you think you borrowed?!
When are you actually going to pay it back?!
那須島はかつて自分のストーカーだった贄川春奈の親をゆすり 金をつくろうとした
And we want it all in cash!
...of his former stalker—Niekawa Haruna—to make some cash.
He came to me by word of those loan sharks called the Awakusu Association and wanted me to look into Haruna's family...
ヤミ金の元締め粟楠会から紹介され
春奈の家族について調査を依頼するためにうちに来て…
Oh, thanks.
どうも
He took the bait hook, line, and sinker.
用意した餌にまんまと食いついた
I'd found out that Niekawa Haruna was Saika.
贄川春奈が 罪歌だっていう情報はつかんでいた
I thought I'd use Haruna to scare him by cornering him and having
her say something like, "You bastard, how dare you steal my money!"
那須島を捕まえて「この野郎オレの金 盗みやがったな」って脅して
春奈を利用してやろうと思ってた
However...
ところがそこに コピーじゃない本物の罪歌が現れた
The real Saika—not just some copy—appeared.
Hm? "What happened to Nasujima," you ask?
えっ？那須島が どうなったかって？
G-Give me your money!
か… 金を出せぇ！
It'd be the best thing in the world for me if Shizu-chan were to die.
オレとしてはシズちゃんが死んでくれたら最高だったんだけど
Well, whatever.
まあいいか ねらいどおり事は運んでくれたわけだし
Everything went just as planned.
Just as you planned?
ねらいどおり？
There are so many more police around.
増えたねぇ 警察の人たち
The mass media are up in arms, too.
マスコミも 大騒ぎっすよ
Something happened in Southern Ikebukuro Park as well, right?
南池袋公園でもなんかあったんだよね？
That was just a clash of wills.
あっちはただのどつきあいだと
It wasn't the Slasher?
斬り裂き魔じゃないんっすか？
What ended up being the cause?
結局なんだったんだろう？ あのおじさんもよく分からないみたいだったし
Even that old guy didn't seem like he knew much.
He didn't remember a thing—just like he'd been hypnotized.
催眠術にでも掛かったみたいになんにも覚えてなかったな
It seems like the police are bracing for a gang war.
警察は カラーギャング同士の抗争と見てるようだ
It's not just the police.
警察だけじゃないっすよ
Would you like to try dying once?
いっぺん死んでみる？
Master, you have mail.
坊ちゃん メールでございます
Huh?
あれ？
What's this?
なんだ？
This...is from the Dollars' leader, isn't it?
これってダラーズのリーダーっすかね？
情報求む
切り裂き魔の情報求む
Calm down, Mikado.
落ち着け 帝人
So...what are you after?
それで何があなたのねらいなの？
Now, this city's been broken into three factions: the Dollars, the Yellow Scarves, and the ethereal sword followers.
これで 街はダラーズと黄巾賊
妖刀軍団の３つに分かれたわけだ
And the ethereal sword followers have spies
in both the Dollars and the Yellow Scarves.
しかも 妖刀組はダラーズにも黄巾賊にもそれぞれ潜入してるときた
To be honest, I would've been fine with Niekawa Haruna leading the ethereal sword group.
正直 妖刀組をつくることができれば
贄川春奈でもよかったんだけどさ
But Sonohara Anri's pretty interesting.
でも園原杏里の方がおもしろいよね
And?
で？
I'm fine with just causing some sparks for now.
今は 火種で十分だよ
If we leave things alone, those sparks will smolder and smoke...
しばらく ほうっておけば その火種がくすぶって くすぶって…
Oh, I can't wait any longer!
オレはもう待ちきれないよ
But the Yellow Scarves were formed by some middle school brat, right?
でも黄巾賊って中学生のガキが つくったんでしょ？
Are they really that formidable?
そんなに大したもの？
The fact that he was able to gather that many people,
despite being a kid...shows that they're already a threat.
ガキのくせしてあれだけの人数をまとめるってのが
すでに脅威なんだよ
Well, it's not like I don't know the Yellow Scarves' shogun...
黄巾賊の将軍ともオレは知らない仲じゃないしねぇ
Don't...drag me back into this.
オレを 引き戻さないでくれ
This is definitely the Dollars' doing!
They do whatever they want!
あいつら好き放題 やりやがって！
We can't do anything without you after all, our superior!
やっぱ オレたち先輩がいないと話になんねぇっす
He's not just your superior, he's the shogun!
先輩じゃねぇ！将軍だろうが！
Uh, I'm sorry!
すみません！
Whatever, it's fine.
いいって いいって
I can't call myself a shogun in this state.
今のオレは将軍なんてもんじゃねぇ
I'm just a simple commoner.
ただの平民
Or, a simple...
つうか ただの…
A simple...high schooler.
ただの… 高校生
Right, I just wanted to be a simple high schooler.
そう ただの高校生でいたかったんだ
I was able to obtain some peace.
オレはオレの平穏を手に入れたわけよ
I was surrounded by good friends and was leading a modestly dangerous life...
仲のいいヤツに囲まれて 適度にデンジャラスな生活をよ
And you've destroyed it.
それをぶっ壊しやがって…
I can't forgive you.
許せねぇ 杏里に手を出したのは本当に許せねぇ
I absolutely can't forgive you for laying a hand on Anri.
We will crush the Slasher, no matter how many of them there are.
たとえ 何人いようが斬り裂き魔は絶対につぶす
And if the Dollars are behind this, then...we'll crush the Dollars.
もしも ダラーズがバックにいるってんなら
そんときはダラーズをつぶす！
You dragged me back into this...
オレを 引き戻しやがって… ちくしょう…
Damn it.
Damn it!
ちくしょう！
I've returned...
オレは戻ってきた
...even though I had no intentions of doing so...
決して戻るつもりはなかったのに ここへ戻ってきた
I've come back here.
So that Saki and I...
オレと沙樹とあの男の過去に決着をつけるために
...can settle things with that guy's past.
Next Time: Life and Death are in the Hands of Fate.
制作：lastzzz akira 安静の云 アキラ
漫游字幕组
http://popgo.net/bbs